

Muhammad Junaid Raza

LUMS, Opposite Sector U, DHA, Lahore, Pakistan Mobile: +923124145514; Email: mjunaidr3@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

A result-oriented and ambitious professional with strong interests in Security Operations/Research, DevOps and Python Development currently working as an MSSP-Security Engineer and open for an opportunity to further experience and knowledge in a challenging and encouraging work environment.

CURRENT ROLE

Ebryx (Pvt.) Ltd.

Security Engineer (MSSP)

May 2020 - Present

- Analysis of incidents and escalation as/if needed
- Creating requirements and scopes for deployments after consulting with the client
- Creating thorough deployment plans
- Building and implementing deployment and configuration guides for the deployment of SIEM/SOAR solutions at the client-side
- Conducting trainings for colleagues and clients
- Monitoring of client environment from SIEM and developing/fine-tuning responses using SOAR solutions.
- So far, I have worked with:
 - o Azure & Azure Sentinel and its deployment across the organization.
 - Analysis and administration of QRadar, ELK stack, Crowdstrike, CarbonBlack, AWS Cloudtrail, and other solutions, and GCP, etc.

Software Engineer

November 2018 – May 2020

June 2014 - June 2018

- Worked for Automation mainly, including side tasks:
 - DevOps implementation
 - Training new teammates
 - o Preparations of product guides and documents before release
 - Product review and new features pitch
 - Developing/building new integrations for orchestrator.
- So far, I have worked with:

DevOps: Bitbucket/GitLab, Jenkins, Artifactory (Nexus OSS3), Building (PyInstaller)

Packaging (dpkg-deb), Ansible

Languages/Frameworks/Libraries: Python, Coffee Script, Shell Scripting, Selenium, Protractor,

RESTful APIs

Development/Tracking systems and methodologies: GitHub, Testrail, JIRA, Confluence, Agile **Security Tools:** Nessus, Wazuh HIDS, burpsuite, Metasploit, nikto, nmap, Anyrun, Cuckoo Sandbox,

Virustotal, NeutrinoAPI, HackerTarget, Shodan, RecordedFuture, WhoAPI, PEiD, Dependency Walker,

PEView, ProcMon, Process Explorer, RegShot, WireShark **Other Products and Tools:** VSphere, Kubernetes, Postman

AWS: EC2, S3, VPC, IAM, Cognito, Rekognition, SNS/SQS

EDUCATION

Lahore University of Management Sciences

BS (Electrical Engineering) - CGPA: 3.20

Relevant Courses: Network Security, Network Centric Computing, Computer Networks, Network Protocols and Performance, Machine Learning, Feedback Control Systems

PROJECTS

Smartphone Apps Fingerprinting using Network Traffic

In this project we captured Network Traffic being MITM and analyzed the traffic using Machine Learning to guess the Smartphone Application being used. We built a temporal profile of every user connected to our internet service. This profile is helpful in network security forensics and for providing better services by ISP.

Decentralizing HVAC using IoT

HVAC systems use lots of power and a complete HVAC system has to be turned on even if only one person is sitting in the building. We brought an idea to replace HVAC by individual AC, Heater, Fan etc. in every office and connecting them together using IoT. This helps control the devices remotely and a synchronous as well as asynchronous operation for whole-building, individual use respectively. This also reduces the monthly power usage by roughly 50%.

Weather Controlled Home Automation using Microcontroller and Xbee

Simple and low-cost implementation of home automation using Xbees along with sensors. The Xbee sends sensor data to Microcontroller which performs suitable actions after analyzing the data.

Obstacle Avoiding Robot Edge Avoiding Robot LFR-Line Following Robot

EXPERIENCE

Lahore University of Management Sciences (LUMS)

Student Intern - Information Systems and Technology (IST) - Computing and Networking

July 2016 - June 2018

IST -Information Systems and Technology- is a department at LUMS that provides students with IT facilities ranging from IT-Labs to fast Internet connections. I decided to work at IST to get an exposure of professional environment and to be able to experience working alongside routine education.

Teaching Assistant - MGHSS - Education

Jan 2018 - May 2018

I have served as a teaching assistant at Mushtaq Gurmani School of Humanities and Social Sciences, managing and organizing tutorials and other grading instruments for a class of 40 students.

Education Ambassador - NOP Center - Education

June 2016 - July 2016

As an Education Ambassador, my task was to reach out to the young and bright yet financially poor students and inform them about scholarships. I am still a part of this program and several students got selected from my area.

Coaching Session IT-Instructor - NOP Center - Education

June 2016 - July 2016

LUMS conducts a coaching session every year to familiarize A-Level/FSc students with University Life and conducts workshops on communication skill, IT-Introduction etc.

INTERESTS

Cyber Security

DevOps

Python Development

Machine Learning

CERTIFICATIONS/TRAININGS/COURSES

Udemy:

Bash Shell Scripting from Udemy

EdX

AWS Developer - Building on AWS

PluralSight:

- Python Beyond the Basics
- Python Best Practices for Code Quality
- Unit Testing with Python
- Managing Python Packages and Virtual Environments

Medical First Responder (MFR), Emergency Medical Services (EMS) - LUMS

Emergency Medical Services is a student run department at LUMS that provides first aid services to students and faculty at campus. It is a volunteer work and the members work free of cost.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Fully Funded Undergraduate Program under LUMS NOP

2014-2018

LUMS provides scholarships to bright and needy students for study. This scholarship is based on the financial need and performance during tests conducted at LUMS. I was one of the 135 students selected out of around 6000 applications. This grant includes full fee waiver, free hostel facility and a living allowance.

Summer Research Program Grant

2017

Applied for and successfully received grant for 10 weeks Summer Research Program (SRP)

CHIEF MINISTER'S AWARD

2017

Received merit-based Laptop Award from Chief Minister Punjab

EXTRA CURRICULAR

Vice President, IEEE-LUMS

Convener, IEEE-LUMS

Director of Operations, EMS-LUMS

Director of Technicals, Dramaline-LUMS